Fortnightly Club Papers WLU.Coll.0671
Washington and Lee University, University Library Special Collections and Archives
- Papers
  - John W. Knapp, 1984-2012
    - For the Increase and Diffusion of Knowledge, 2001-01-19
    - Containment or Liberation: Unilaterally or Otherwise?, 2003-01-03
    - Dam Foolishness and Despotism, 2008-12-17
    - Citizen Soldiers Of The First Rank, 2012-12-19
    - Nature's Brute: Stonewall Jackson in Lexington and at VMI, 1989-02-17
      Jackson, Thomas Jonathan (Stonewall)
    - Out of the Fiery Furnace, 1991-01-18
    - Rendezvous, 1998-10-23
    - William Weaver against Jordan, Davis & Co.
    - Virginia's Inland Ports, 1984-10-19
    - Through the Ceiling and Beyond, 2005-02-04
    - Remarks on "Through the Ceiling and Beyond", 2005-02-04; Marion, John Hardin
    - Yet Another Bubble, 2010-12-15
    - First Response on "Yet Another Bubble", 2010-12-15
  - Al Lancaster, 1967-1986; Lancaster, Albert Lake
    - Mutual Funds, 1967-12; Lancaster, Albert Lake
    - Käthe Kollwitz, 1974-03-01; Lancaster, Albert Lake
      Kollwitz, Käthe, 1867-1945
    - The Troubled CIA, 1976-03-19; Lancaster, Albert Lake
    - Hymns and Shape-Notes, 1978-03-31; Lancaster, Albert Lake
    - William Henry Ruffner, 1980-01-18; Lancaster, Albert Lake
      Ruffner, William Henry
    - America's Greatest Composer, 1982-02-05; Lancaster, Albert Lake
      Sousa, John Philip
    - Two Memorable Years, 1983-11-18; Lancaster, Albert Lake
    - Yankee Count, 1986-01-17; Lancaster, Albert Lake
    - Alsos, Lancaster, Albert Lake
  - Greenlee D. Letcher, Letcher, Greenlee D. (Greenlee Davidson)
    - Photograph of Rev. William McCutchan Morrison, 1926-08
      Morrison, William McCutchan, Reverend
    - The Federal Commerce Power, 1963; Light, Charles Porterfield
    - William McCutchan Morrison, The African Missionary, 1925-11-20; Letcher, Greenlee D. (Greenlee Davidson)
    - Untitled Paper on Major George Marshall, 1968-10-25
      Marshall, George C. (George Catlett)
  - Tom V. Litzenburg, 1994-2008; Litzenburg, Thomas V., Jr.
    - Whence and Whither This Vision of Paradise Without a Wall?, 1994-02-18; Litzenburg, Thomas V., Jr.
    - The Pure Geometry of the Circle and the Square -- In the Antique Manner, 1996-03-29; Litzenburg, Thomas V., Jr.
    - A Vision Shines Out of the Valley... All Honey-gold and Tightly Packed, 1999-10; Litzenburg, Thomas V., Jr.
    - All in the Golden Afternoon, 2001-10; Litzenburg, Thomas V., Jr.
    - A Vicar's Self-Educated Daughter, 2003-11-14; 2008-03; Litzenburg, Thomas V., Jr.
      Austen, Jane, 1775-1817
    - Whereof one cannot speak..., 2006-03-25; 2006-07-01; Litzenburg, Thomas V., Jr.
  - Marion and McClung, 1963-2011; Marion, John Hardin
    - The Most Excellent Canopy, 1963-02-22
  - Jim Morgan, 1958-1985
    - Discussion Led by Jim Morgan
    - Alpha, Beta, Gamma, 1958-10-03
    - The Forgotten Academy, 1967-10-06
    - Time, 1969-03-28
    - Reply to R. Lyle's Paper, 1972-03-03
    - Seventy-Five Years and The Fortnightly, 1974-12-13
    - Buried Treasure, Buried Hopes, 1985-03-01
  - Malcolm Muir, Jr., -2012
    - Playing with Fire: Sherman's March Through Georgia and the Carolinas, 2004
      Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh)
    - The Mother of All Cover-ups, 2008-10-29
    - Weighted Off--and Found Wanting, 2010-11-10
    - The Rectification of Names, 2012-10-31
  - Brian C. Murchison, 1994-2011; Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - April Fool, 1994-01-21; Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - Free Speech, Yesterday and Today, 1995-12-01; Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - Justice's Gem, 2000-02-18; Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - First Response to Justice's Gem, 2000-02-18; Hadsel, Fred L.
      Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - Giamatti, 2004-01-02; Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - Midnight Appointment, 2006-01-20; Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - A Crime in Hopewell, Murchison, Brian Cameron
    - Blogging and Anonymity, 2009-2010; Murchison, Brian Cameron (Box 5)
    - Direct, Immediate, Irreparable, 2011-12-14; Murchison, Brian Cameron
  - H. David Natkin, 2005-2011; Natkin, H. David
    - The Trial of the Infidel, 2005-10-14; Natkin, H. David
    - DOM (Dominion of Melchizedek), 2007-10-10; Natkin, H. David
    - You Can't Go Home Again, 2009-10-14; Natkin, H. David (Box 5)
    - The White Squaw, 2011-09-28; Natkin, H. David
  - William Old, III, 1971-1998; Old, William, III
    - Zocaloe Visited and Revisited, Old, William, III
    - The Big One, 1971-01-22; Old, William, III
    - A Lady and an Island, 1976-11-12; Old, William, III
    - 6,000 Strong!, 1985-11-15; Old, William, III
    - America's Adopted Royal Family, 1989-12-15; Old, William, III
    - Restless Spirit, 1992-01-23; Old, William, III
    - Who, 1995-11-03; Old, William, III
    - Now You See It!, 1998-02-28; Old, William, III
  - Eric Osborne, 2009-2013
    - Consequences of Distant Force, 2009-01-21
    - Winning Isn't All It's Cracked Up to Be, 2013-01-23
  - Frank Pancake, 1953; Pancake, Frank
    - Highways in the Air, 1953-03-06; Pancake, Frank
  - Frank Parsons, 1979-2006; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - Untitled Paper, Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - W. Eugene Smith, Photographer, 1979-11-30; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
      Smith, W. Eugene
    - From Gator to Gone in Four Years, 1984-02-17; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - Soldiers Like Other Soldiers?, 1986-02-14; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - World Views - Arnold's Franks, and Pogo's, 1987-11-27; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - New Cages For The Zoo, 1992-02-07; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - Tarnished Gold?, 1989-11-03; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - War As Memory, 1993-03-19; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - A Bridge Just Far Enough, 1993-12-03; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - The Name Is Nick, 2000-03-10; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - Applied Statistical Probabilities, 2001-12-14; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - How I Nearly Became a Presbyterian, 2004-03-26; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
    - A & E: Fakin' It, 2006-03-10; Parsons, Frank (Frank Arthur)
  - Matthew W. Paxton Jr., 1961-2011; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - The Great Chapel Debate, 1961-11-03; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - The Rockbridge Alum Springs, 1963-12-06; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - Lexington's Great Events, 1967-11-10; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - A Judge's School, 1969-10-17; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - Like a Handful of Mortar, 2002-01-04; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - A Little Gypsy Magic, 2003-12-02; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - The Catalan-Rockbridge Connection, 2005-10-28; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
    - An Arrival at the Baths, 2007-11-07
    - The American Dream in a Boxcar, 2009-11-11 (Box 5)
    - Rolling Your Own, 2011-10-26; Paxton, Matthew White, Jr.
  - Tobias R. Philbin, Jr., 1990-1993; Philbin, Tobias
    - Les Bâtards, 1990-03-02; Philbin, Tobias
    - Memoir of Metz, 1993-01-08; Philbin, Tobias
  - K. S. Purdie, 1948-1962; Purdie, K. S.
    - The Purchase of Alaska, 1948-01-23; Purdie, K. S.
    - Forty Years and the Fortnightly, 1962-02-23; Purdie, K. S.
  - Reveley, 1989; Reveley, Walter Taylor; 1 Item
    - Pot Pourri, 1989-01-06; Reveley, Walter Taylor
  - Steven Riethmiller, 2000-2002; Riethmiller, Steven; 2 Item
    - Nunquam Otiosus, 2000-11-3; Riethmiller, Steven
    - The Search for the Magic Bullet, 2002-01-17; Riethmiller, Steven
  - William W. Pusey III, 1951-1992; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Thomas Wolfe, 1951-10-19; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
      Wolfe, Thomas
    - The End of the Rainbow: Three Modern "Utopian" Novels, 1953-10-02; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - The Nuremberg Trials: Review and Re-Examination, 1955-10-07; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - The Failure of a Conspiracy: July 20, 1944, 1957-11-01; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Flight to Flensburg, 1959-12-18; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Reflections on the Study of Foreign Languages, 1963-12-10; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb) (Box 5)
    - Soviet Literature, 1965-11-19 (Box 5)
    - An Innocent in Russia, 1929, 1967-11-17 (Box 5)
    - Alfried Krupp, 1969-10-31 (Box 5)
    - The Interrupted Dream, 1974-01-09; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Today Germany..., 1975-01-09; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Junius Fishburn: Latin Scholar Abroad, 1978-03-17; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
      Fishburn, Junius Parker
    - Lexington's Female Academy, 1979-12-14; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - The Way It Was -- I Think, 1982-03-05; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Lillie and Virginia, 1984-05-28; 1984-01-06; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Eight Days in May -- 1970 (In Retrospection), 1985-11-29; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Washington and Lee University in Fiction, 1987-10-05; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Theater in Staunton, Virginia (1875-1912), 1989-12-01; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
    - Celebrities (I Have Known), 1992-02-26; Pusey, William W., III (William Webb)
  - Henry Louis Smith, 1928; Smith, Henry Louis; 1 Item
    - The Culture Afforded by Scientific Study, 1928-01-04; Smith, Henry Louis
  - Taylor Sanders, 1990-1994; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II; 7 Item
    - Response to Taylor Saunders Fortnightly Talk, 1990-10-12; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
      Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II
    - Stonehenge Choreographed?, 1990-10; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II
    - TR, 1993-01-22; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II
    - ISIS and the Ardvaark, 1994-11-16; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II
    - Lumpers v. Splitters, 2005-01; Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II
    - Pendleburly of Crete, Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II
    - Blue Grass Paradoxes, Sanders, Irwin Taylor, II
  - Edgar Spencer, 1990-2011; Spencer, Edgar Winston
    - All Outdoors was at once a Laboratory for Research and a Temple for Worship, 1990-02-02; Spencer, Edgar Winston
    - Powell -- One of the illustrious obscure, 1992-03-06; Spencer, Edgar Winston
      Powell, John Wesley
    - Visions, 1998-04-03; Spencer, Edgar Winston
    - As Viewed from Afar, 2002-01-18; Spencer, Edgar Winston
    - Views Across the Valley, 2004-01-16; Spencer, Edgar Winston
    - Under the Mountain Peaks, 2006-02-10; Spencer, Edgar Winston
    - People in the Puzzle, 2007-12-12
    - Terra Incognita, 2009-12-16 (Box 5)
      Spencer, Edgar Winston
    - Half-Way Around the World, 2011-11-30; Spencer, Edgar Winston
  - Joseph Spivey, 2001-2005; Spivey, Joseph M., III
    - Untitled Paper, 2001; Spivey, Joseph M., III
    - Faust in the Age of Innocence, 2005-12-16; Spivey, Joseph M., III
  - Roy Steinheimer, 1975; Steinheimer, Roy Lee, Jr.
    - A National Court of Appeals?, 1975-11-14; Steinheimer, Roy Lee, Jr.
    - Profession or Trade Association, Steinheimer, Roy Lee, Jr.
  - Marcellus Stow, 1941-1951; Stow, Marcellus Henry
    - Mineral Resources of Participants in World War II and World War III, 1949-02-25; Stow, Marcellus Henry
    - The History of Virginia, 1951-10-05; Stow, Marcellus Henry
  - Matthew Tuchler, 2009-2013; Tuchler, Matthew F.
    - Lies, Damn Lies and Statistics: Conditional Probability, 2009-03-04; Tuchler, Matthew F.
    - Is a Model Anything More Than Good Looking, 2010-02-03
    - The Reality of Truth and the Truth of Reality, 2011-03-02; Tuchler, Matthew F.
    - Hazing and the Devil in All of Us, 2013-03-06; Tuchler, Matthew F.
  - Spencer C. Tucker, 2008-2013
    - Resurgam, 2008-10-15
    - Unconditional Surrender: The River War in the Western Theater, 1862, 2010-11-09
    - The Chesapeake-Leopard Affair, 2012-10
    - "The Most Bold and Daring Act of the Age" Captain Stephen Decatur, Jr. and the Burning of the Philadelphia
    - The Far North, 2013-11-13; Spencer, Edgar Winston
  - Robert H. Tucker, 1918-1950; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - The Budget System and Popular Control, 1918-04; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Social Aspects of Workmen's Compensation Laws, 1923-04; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Stabilizing the Dollar, 1928-01-06; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - County Organization and Management, 1931-11-20; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Significant Trends in College Education, 1934-01-05; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Socialism and Social Reform, 1936-01-24; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - The Public Utility Act of 1935: Its Background and Significance, 1938-01-07; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Some Aspects of Intergovernmental Tax Exemption, 1940-01-05; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Some Problems of War Finance, 1942-01-09; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Financing the Second World War, 1942-08; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Progress in State Government, 1944-01-07; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - National Labor Policy, 1948-01; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - The Functions of Government, 1950-01; Tucker, Robert Henry
    - Some Factors Affecting Our Future Relations with the Philippine Islands, 1950-12-15; Tucker, Robert Henry
  - Carrington C. Tutwiler, Jr., 1966-1987
    - In Search of Helen
    - In Defense of Presbyterians
    - The Road to Ithaca, 1966-12-16
    - News From Crete, 1970-12-18
    - The Discovery of the Tomb of Tutenkhamun, 1974-02-15
    - The Centennial Summer of Jackson C. Lee, 1976-03-05
    - Jefferson's Bible, 1977-10-07
    - Major Preston's Decision, 1984-03-16
    - That Winged Chariot, 1985-11-01
    - Time and Again, 1987-03-27
  - Lewis Tyree, Jr., 1991-2002; Tyree, Lewis
    - Lewal's Maxim AMERICAN RISK TAKING AND INNOVATION (Where the marketplace is the laboratory), 1993-03-05; Tyree, Lewis
    - The Battle Fought at Lexington, June 11, 1864, 1995-03-31; Tyree, Lewis
    - An Engineer's Engineer, 1997-11-21; Tyree, Lewis
    - Courage or Duty Was Heavier Than a Mountain or Speaking the Unspeakable, 1999-12-03; 2002-02-15; Tyree, Lewis
  - Unknown Authors, 1976-2008
    - Behold, a Pale Horse
    - Bajamar - Shallow Sea, 1976-02-20
    - The Weather
    - Iran and the Middle East
    - The Most Horrible Battle in History: The Battle of Verdun, 2000-03-24
    - Massacres Happen
    - A Polite Mausoleum, 2004-10-29
    - Richmond, Between the Wars
    - On the South River in 1638
  - Dan C. Vance, 2012; Vance, Dan C.
    - Macondo, 2012-02-01; Vance, Dan C.
  - Sam S. Walker, 1985; Walker, Sam S.
    - Fustest With The Mostest, 1985-03-29; Walker, Sam S.
  - Jim Warren, 2012; Warren, Jim
    - Whitman, Poet of Civil War, 2012-02-15; Warren, Jim
      Whitman, Walt
  - Charles C. Watson, 2001-2012; Watson, Charles C.
    - Education Under the Bushel Basket, 2001-01-05; Watson, Charles C.
    - Unnatural Decision, 2002-10-04; Watson, Charles C.
    - Notes From The Twentieth Century, 2004-10-01; Watson, Charles C.
    - The Horror! The Horror!, 2010-09-01; Watson, Charles C.
    - Notes From the Twentieth Century Cassette Tape, 2004-10; Watson, Charles C.
    - Founding Events, 2008-10-01; Watson, Charles C.
    - H is History, 2012-10; Watson, Charles C.
  - William W. Watt, 1972-1980; Watt, William Joseph
    - The Education of a Scientist, 1972-10-06; Watt, William Joseph
    - A Grand Opera, Watt, William Joseph
    - A Student of Dr. Howe's -- S. C. Lind, 1975-03-21; Watt, William Joseph
      Lind, Samuel C.
    - The Chemistry of Cannabis, Watt, William Joseph
    - Off Limits?, 1979-03-02; Watt, William Joseph
    - Swan Lake, 1980-02-15; Watt, William Joseph
  - William W. Watt, 1983-1992; Watt, William Joseph; 5 Item
    - The First Law, 1983-03-25`; Watt, William Joseph
    - Of Lena Geyer, 1984-12-14; Watt, William Joseph
    - Thought for Food, 1986-10-31; Watt, William Joseph
    - Theophilus, 1989-03-03; Watt, William Joseph
    - Martha, 1992; Watt, William Joseph
  - William W. Watt, 1994-2001; Watt, William Joseph; 6 Item
    - A Sacred Oratio, 1994-12-02
    - Noble Prize Winners I Have Known, 1996-11-22; Watt, William Joseph
    - James Lewis Howe and the Fortnightly Club, 1999-01-08; Watt, William Joseph
      Howe, James Lewis
    - The Resort of the Century, 2001; Watt, William Joseph
    - The Labors of Linus, Watt, William Joseph
      Pauling, Linus
    - The Prize, Watt, William Joseph
  - Lt. Col. Paul Welles, 1946; Welles, Paul N.; 1 Item
    - Whither USA?, 1946-12-13; Welles, Paul N.
  - H.T. Williams, 1989-2007; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.; 8 Item
    - Piles and Gadgets, 1989-03-17; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - "...and, in addition...", 1993-02-05; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - In the Eyes of One Beholder, 1996-03-15; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - Always Good Ships, 1998-03-20; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - Much Ado About Nothing, 1999-10-01; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - Blue Point, 2002-03-01; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - If Two Wrongs Don't Make a Right,..., 2003-10-31; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - The Heir to Lou Gerhig, 2005-11-11; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr.
    - Paying Bills, 2007-10-24
    - Second, 2009-10-28; Williams, Harry Thomas, Jr. (Box 5)
  - Jon Williams, 2011; Williams, Jon; 1 Item
    - Ragged, 2011-11-09; Williams, Jon
  - Wilson, 1985-1986; 2 Item
    - Buried Songs, Buried Lives, 1985-02-01
    - On the Face of it!, 1986-12-12
  - Unknown authors, 2008
    - Jailed for Speech, 2008-01-23
    - A Time to Go Home (Box 5)
  - Binder of Papers, 2014-2015; Adams, James L.; Brooke, George M., III; 1 Volumes
    - In Honored Glory, 2014-10-01
    - Nathanael Greene, 2014-10-15
    - On Obesity, 2014-10-29
    - The Unfolding of Miscalculations, 2014-11-12
    - Cowboys and Indians...and All That Jazz, 2014-12-03
    - Bluff to Win Without Cashing In, 2014-12-17
    - Henry Fleete, 2015-01-07
    - "How Do You Know You're Not Dreaming Right Now?" - A brief history of the Virginia Program at Oxford, 1980-2012, 2015-01-21
    - Peccavi, 2015-02-04
    - "Innocent Bystanders", 2015-02-18
    - A Prayer and a Struggle, 2015-03-04
    - Learning More and More about Less and Less, 2015-03-18; Tuchler, Matthew F.